Of course there's an outside beyond here.
這裡之外，當然有個外面
We don't know what happens behind the teachers' doors,
我們不知道老師們在背地裡搞什麼鬼
or where our food comes from, or what's inside the vents.
或者食物是從哪裡來的、通風口裡有什麼
All these gaps make me think of an "outside."
這些落差讓我認為外面確實存在
Why would Mimihime want to go outside?
為什麼彌美姬想去外面呢？
Do you like Mimihime?
你喜歡彌美姬嗎？
Well, yeah.
嗯，對呀
I see.
是喔
Are you okay?
你還好吧？
I'm going back to my room.
我要回房間了
-I'll come with you. -It's okay.
-我陪你回去 -不用了
Don't worry. I'll use the auto-drive.
別擔心，我會開啟自動行駛
TWO CONFESSIONS
《兩人的告白》
Kuku, that drawing!
玖玖，那張畫！
Kona gave it to me. Isn't it nice?
小奈給我的，很不錯吧？
Give it here.
給我
Why? He gave it to me.
為什麼？這是他給我的
Kona promised to give it to me.
小奈答應了要給我
No fair! You get them all!
不公平，為什麼全都要給你？
I like Kona's drawings, too. Why can't I get one?
我也喜歡小奈的畫 我為什麼不能有一張？
-You're right. -Huh?
妳說的對
Sorry, Kuku.
對不起，玖玖
Hey! What's that for?
喂，現在是怎樣？
Why did you give it to Kuku?
你為什麼把那張畫給了玖玖？
You promised me.
你答應過我
I'll draw the next one for you.
我下一張畫好就給你
Really?
真的嗎？
I like the things you imagine.
我很喜歡你想像出來的畫面
Geez. Tokio is such a crybaby.
天啊，時男真是個愛哭包
Just because Kuku got that drawing.
只不過是因為玖玖拿到了那張畫
1 NEW MESSAGE
（一則新訊息）
A message from Mimihime?
彌美姬傳來的？
So sweaty.
流了滿身汗
Wake up, Maru. It's the Man-eater, Hiruko!
醒醒，小丸，是食人者，蛭子出現了
No good. It's locked.
不妙，鎖住了
I'll go out through the bathroom.
我從浴室出去
Wake up.
醒醒吧
She fed us some sort of drug to put us to sleep.
她給我們下藥，要我們睡到不醒人事
You two! It's dangerous. Get back inside!
你們兩個！很危險，快進來
I told you we can kill it.
我就說了我們能夠殺了牠
The Kiru-Beam?
貴留光線？
Fully charged.
電力滿格
-There! -Huh?
在那裡
I'm okay. Just tripped.
我沒事，只是絆倒了
What was that?
那是什麼東西呀？
Maru, try throwing something.
小丸，拿東西朝牠丟過去
Okay!
好
An ultrasonic blast?
超音波轟擊
No, I see something flickering.
不對，我看到有東西在閃爍
That's not the sound of its voice.
那不是牠的聲音
That's the sound of its whip things!
那是牠揮鞭的聲音
There are three whips on each arm.
每條手臂上有三條鞭子
I can't get close unless we destroy them.
除非毀掉鞭子，不然我無法靠近牠
Three? Gotta get the wings, too.
三條？也得毀了翅膀才行
Are there enough bullets?
子彈數量夠嗎？
No, three and three makes six.
不夠，三加三等於六
I know that.
我知道
Wait…
等等…
Where is it?
牠跑哪裡去了？
This way!
這裡
Yes!
好耶
I hit an arm and a wing!
我射中了一條手臂和一邊的翅膀
What a sniper.
好個神射手
The gun's range is a bit longer than the whips.
這把槍的射程比鞭子稍微長了一些
If I can get a bit closer, I can hit the other arm.
如果我能靠近一點 就能夠射中另一條手臂
Then you can go after it, Maru.
然後你就可以攻擊牠，小丸
-Okay. -Here goes.
-好 -來吧
You'll lose an arm if you get too close. Be careful.
如果妳靠得太近會失去一條手臂喔，小心
I was trying not to think about that…
沒事幹嘛提醒我啦…
Here!
吃我一槍
The manager?
老闆娘？
Run! Get away!
快跑，快逃
Stop! That's my son.
住手，那是我兒子
So your son was eaten by that thing.
那個東西把妳的兒子吃下肚了
No. Yuto went inside it, and it became Yuto!
不是，悠人進入了牠的身體 牠變成了悠人
You drugged us to protect the Man-eater.
妳對我們下藥是為了保護食人者
I was almost eaten by one, so I know…
我曾經差一點被食人者吃掉 所以我很清楚…
It cuts up its prey and absorbs them.
牠會將獵物切開，然後開始吸食
But I'm sorry, I don't think those who are eaten take over its body.
但很抱歉，我不認為 被吃掉的人會接管牠的身體
But that is Yuto!
但牠就是悠人
He protects me.
牠會保護我
He even rescued me when I was attacked.
甚至在我被攻擊的時候救過我
Fine. I get it.
好吧，我明白了
Sis.
姊
I'm out of shots.
我的子彈都用光了
If it's not a threat, there's no reason to kill it.
如果牠不構成威脅，就沒必要殺了牠
Yuto!
悠人
They understand.
他們能夠理解
I'm safe.
我沒事了
They can communicate?
他們能夠溝通？
See?
看吧？
Damn it!
可惡
Did you see?
你看到了嗎？
The whip only swings in one direction.
牠只會朝著同一個方向揮動鞭子
So there's a pause between attacks.
所以兩波攻擊之間會有空檔
How can you think like that? Someone just died!
妳怎麼說得出這些話？ 才剛剛有人死在我們面前耶
If I don't, we won't survive.
如果我不這麼做，我們就別想活下去
Sorry.
抱歉
I'll kill it.
我會殺了牠
I got in!
我伸進去了
Why didn't Hiruko attack the manager until yesterday?
為什麼蛭子直到昨天才攻擊老闆娘呢？
Maybe it was her son's consciousness,
或許是她兒子的良知吧
or it instinctively kept her alive.
也或許牠直覺性地留她活口
Since its prey gathers around this place…
因為牠的臘物會聚集在這個地方…
Maybe she fed the guests to her son…
或許她把客人餵食給她兒子
Let's stop.
別說了
The truth can stay hidden.
沒必要追根究底
We already have enough on our hands.
我們身上的東西已經很足夠了
Looking for "Heaven."
去找天國吧
Oh, the batteries. Want to take them?
要把電池帶走嗎？
Didn't you give them to the manager?
妳不是把電池送給老闆娘了嗎？
Hey, stop that!
住手啦
Sis, have you ever ridden a moving train?
姊，妳坐過行駛中的電車嗎？
I was three during the Great Disaster.
大災難發生的時候我才三歲
I wouldn't remember even if I had.
即使坐過我也不會記得
Wait.
等等
If you're 20, then you were five--
如果妳現在20歲，那時候妳應該是五歲…
Hey!
喂
Is that water safe?
那裡的水安全嗎？
It's okay, I'm just rinsing my mouth.
沒事啦，我只是在嗽口
Plus, it doesn't taste weird.
況且它的味道不會怪怪的
It's such a nice day.
今天天氣真好
Perfect for sailing.
最適合出航
KIRUKO-MARU
（貴留子，小丸）
Okay.
好的
Let's go down.
我們下去吧
It's shakier than I thought!
比我以為的更晃
Get on gently!
動作輕一點啦
Step like a feather.
像羽毛一樣踩上來
That's impossible!
怎麼可能啦？
All right!
太好了
It's floating somehow.
竟然浮起來了耶
If those old guys were telling the truth, Tomato Heaven is right in front of us.
如果那些大叔說的是實話 蕃茄天國就近在眼前啦
Kind of late to ask, but there aren't any sharks or crocodiles, right?
現在問好像有點晚了 但這裡不會有鯊魚或鱷魚吧？
-Don't know. -Hey!
-不確定 -喂
The only thing I can kill is Hiruko!
我只懂得除掉蛭子
You gotta do something if a croc shows up.
如果鱷魚出現的話，就得靠妳了
I-- I'll think of something before you get eaten up.
我會在你被吃掉之前想出辦法的
You can't let it bite me. You're the bodyguard!
妳不能讓我被咬，妳是保鏢耶
If I was a crocodile, I'd eat you first.
如果我是鱷魚，我會先吃掉妳
Row! Go all out!
快划，使盡全力
It's not that far.
就快到了
Just keep praying that a carnivore doesn't show up!
你就祈禱肉食動物不會出現吧
Sorry.
抱歉…
It's okay. I'll go get it.
沒關係，我去撿
The teachers-only door.
僅限師長進入
Is the outside behind it?
外面就在那扇門之後嗎？
The ball went over there…
球跑到那裡了…
Go ahead and take it.
去撿吧
There it is.
找到了
Okay, stick there.
好的，黏在這裡
Are you really going to do it? It's dangerous!
你真的要這麼做嗎？很危險耶
They'll get mad if you break it.
如果你弄壞了，他們會生氣
I said it'll be fine.
我說了不會有事的
Now, I'll begin the great experiment!
偉大的實驗就要開始了
Wow!
哇
Amazing.
太驚人了
It's going so high.
到了這麼高的地方
At this rate, it'll go all the way up.
按照這種速度，將能夠抵達頂端
Ouch.
好痛
Why is Shiro the one bleeding?
為什麼流血的是士郎？
What's wrong?
怎麼了嗎？
I get the feeling something else is going to fall.
我有種感覺，會有別的東西掉下來
If this is "Heaven," then my job ends here.
如果這裡是天國 那我的工作就到這裡結束了
KUSAKABE FARM TRESPASSERS WILL BE MERCILESSLY KILLED
（草壁農園，擅自闖入的人 會死無葬身之地）
But you don't know where "Heaven" is, or what you'll do when you get there.
你不知道天國在哪裡 也不知道到了那裡要做什麼
Yup.
對
So my job doesn't end until you're satisfied with the results.
所以在你得到滿意的結果之前 這份工作我會一直做下去
I'll do everything I can, so don't keep any secrets from me.
我會盡我所能，所以別對我隱瞞任何祕密
I'm not hiding anything, but…
我沒有隱瞞任何事，只是…
This.
這個
There's a needle and a drug inside this cylinder.
這個圓桶裡有一根針和一種藥物
There's a guy with the same face as me out there somewhere.
在某個地方有個長得跟我一模一樣的男孩
I was told to inject him with this drug when I find him.
有人要我在找到他之後 向他注射這款藥物
I believe that the person I'm looking for, is in this place called "Heaven."
我認為我要找的這個人 在一個叫做「天國」的地方
And after the shot?
藥物注射完成之後呢？
Don't know. He'll get better?
不知道，他會好起來？
Anyway, I was told it would help everyone.
總之，有人告訴我它能夠幫助每個人
I don't know anything else.
其他的我就一概不知了
Did she tell you anything?
她沒跟妳說什麼嗎？
You were the last one to see Mikura.
見到御藏最後一面的人是妳
Pull it down.
拉下來
Protect Maru with this.
用這個來保護小丸
I will. Where should I take him?
我會的，我該帶他去哪裡？
Hea…
天…
She only told me to take you to "Heaven."
她只告訴了我要帶你去天國
What're you guys doing?
你們在做什麼？
Hello.
大家好
You don't look like bandits.
你們看起來不像是強盜
Are you locals?
你們是本地人嗎？
No, we walked all the way from Tokyo.
不是，我們從東京一路走來這裡
And you found us?
然後妳找到了我們？
Someone told us about this place.
有人告訴我們這個地方
It's like "Heaven."
這裡就像是天國
So you came here on purpose.
所以你們是特地過來的
You want to join us?
你們想加入我們嗎？
You see, this kid is--
是說，這孩子…
Let's take them to the Leader.
帶他們去見園長吧
This way. Come on in.
這裡，進來吧
-Taisuke! -Yeah!
-退助 -好耶
If you're from Tokyo, then you climbed down the big fault?
既然是從東京來的 表示你們爬過了大斷層囉？
Oh, that huge cliff?
那座巨大的懸崖嗎？
It was so tiring. We made a raft and crossed over.
太累人了，所以我們做了一艘木筏過河
That's dangerous!
很危險耶
Saltwater crocs swim in those waters.
鹹水鱷魚會在那裡出沒
What?
什麼？
There were crocs. Crocs!
鱷魚，有鱷魚！
You weren't eaten so don't think about it.
你又沒被吃掉，別再想這件事了
I'm Kusakabe, the leader of this village.
我是草壁，這個村莊的園長
This is my wife, Momoko.
這是我太太，桃子
As you see, we're just a rag-tag bunch.
如你們所見，我們是一群烏合之眾
We tried to cling to the past, and dreamt of reviving our society,
我們曾貪戀著過去，試圖復興這個社會
but many people grew tired of such futile hopes.
但許多人開始對這種無謂的希望感到厭煩
So we chose a simple life, living off the fruits of the earth.
所以我們選擇了這種簡單生活 靠大地的果實過活
It was just my father and a few farmers,
一開始只有我父親和一些農夫
but we soon became this large family.
但很快就演變成了這個大家庭
Wow. That's awesome.
哇，太棒了
I heard this is "Tomato Heaven," is that right?
我聽說這裡是蕃茄天國，對吧？
It used to be full of tomatoes.
之前種滿了蕃茄
Now we can grow all kinds of local crops.
現在我們栽種了各式各樣的當地農作物
Tomato Heaven is such a nice place.
蕃茄天國真是個好地方
A farm this size is amazing, but something feels off.
這種規模的農場真的很棒 但我總覺得哪裡怪怪的
They are nice enough to feed us, though.
至少他們人還不錯，請我們吃飯
Well, if you think so, Sis.
嗯，如果妳這麼想的話，姊
Make your own opinions.
有點主見好嗎？
Since no one's reacting to your face, I guess that look-alike guy isn't here.
既然沒人對你的臉有反應 我想長得跟你一樣的男孩不在這裡
Right, that's one way to find out.
對耶，這麼說很有道理耶
As if, did you not realize that this entire time?
難道這段時間你一直沒想到這一點嗎？
That face!
那張臉！
You're Kiriko Takehaya!
妳是竹早桐子
The electro-kart racer!
電動卡丁車賽車手
No, you got it wrong.
不是，你認錯人了
I was a huge fan. Look, I still have your photo.
我是妳的超級粉絲 妳看，我還留著妳的相片
How long since you disappeared?
妳失蹤多久啦？
Five years? I was so worried.
五年嗎？我超擔心的
There were rumors that you lost it after killing your brother in a race.
有謠言說妳在賽車場上 害死你弟之後就發瘋了
Hey!
喂
She doesn't look--
她長得才不像…
They might look alike, but that's not her.
她們或許長得很像，但不是同一個人啦
-But-- -I said you got the wrong person!
-但是… -我說了你認錯人了
So sorry.
實在是很抱歉
Wait!
等等
I just…
我只是…
This! Sis, doesn't this look familiar?
姊，妳看，這是不是有點眼熟？
Maybe, maybe not…
好像有，也好像沒有…
I got it! It's here!
我知道了，在這裡！
Don't go around groping someone's leg.
別隨便亂摸別人的大腿
No, this.
不是啦，是這個
Where did you get this box?
這個盒子是哪裡來的？
Not sure.
不太確定
We're always taking vegetables and stuff to Tokyo on the ship.
我們總是會用船載著青菜和貨物去東京
Boxes like this can come from anywhere.
這種盒子可能會出現在任何地方
You can get to Tokyo by ship?
可以坐船到東京？
Wow.
是喔
If we look into this logo, won't we find a connection to you, Maru?
如果我們調查這個標誌 會不會查到跟你有關的事呢，小丸？
At least, we'll find out what it is.
至少我們會查出這個標誌是怎麼回事
-Right here. -Other than here!
-這裡就是啦 -除了這裡之外的地方啦
Asakusa during Kiriko Takehaya's era.
竹早桐子稱霸時期的淺草吧
Thanks a lot.
多謝你了
That helps.
這很有幫助
If we don't get any more information, let's get on the ship back to Tokyo.
要是沒辦法查到更多情報 我們就坐船回東京吧
Okay.
好啊
Japan is much bigger than I thought.
日本比我想像的大多了
We'll never find "Heaven" this way.
用這種方式一輩子別想找到天國
It's a waste to go back,
回去恐怕是浪費時間
but if we investigate your background, I think we'll get to Heaven faster.
還不如調查你的背景 我認為這是更快找到天國的辦法
Found some potatoes! Want one?
找到了一些馬鈴薯耶，要拿一顆嗎？
They won't know if one is missing.
他們不會發現少了一顆的
What's wrong? You don't look good. Seasick?
怎麼了？你的臉色不太好，生病了嗎？
Forget about Heaven.
別管天國了
We won't find it.
我們找不到的
I want to live on the farm with you.
我想跟妳一起生活在這個農場裡
Not me.
我才不要
Farming all day and getting high at night…
白天耕種，晚上呼麻作樂
What nature? It's just a bunch of idiots.
什麼大自然啊？只不過是一群笨蛋
That's not what I mean.
我不是那個意思啦
I could help you with your job.
我可以協助妳的工作
I-- I like you, Sis!
姊，我喜歡妳
DO NOT ENTER
（禁止進入）
Hey! Confessing in such a place doesn't do either of us any good.
喂，在這種地方告白對我們沒有任何好處
I'm serious!
我是認真的
Give me a serious answer.
請妳認真回答我
Wait, stop! Get off!
等等，住手，放開我
Forcing is--
用暴力實在是…
I'm so, so, sorry.
實在是非常抱歉
It's okay. Thanks, though.
沒關係啦，謝謝你了
Hey, I'm going to tell you something. So listen.
是說，我現在要告訴你一件事，你聽好
It might be crazy, but I'm being serious, so I want you to understand.
這或許很瘋狂，但我是認真的 我希望你能夠理解
My body is a woman's,
我的身體是個女人
but in here, my mind is a man's.
但在這裡，我的心智是個男人
So… I'm a man.
所以…我是個男人
What?
什麼？